Hello, everyone. Welcome back to PostgreSQL tutorial series. So today, we are going to explore for
how to drop column for the PostgreSQL table using for the drop column statement. Okay.
So here in the dropping column from the PostgreSQL table is a common task in database management.
It allows us to remove the unnecessary columns and streamline for our database structure. Okay.
So first of all, I can create for the first example for dropping a single column. Okay.
So first, I can use the
implicit table because in the simplest table, I can just use. So
first, I can type for the select then from here, the
employees. Okay. So perfect. And now just select all and execute and you can see here.
Now I can go the department ID and also the department names are now just go for. Okay.
So here, I can go here. So first of all, I can choose for the database or the postgreSQL.
And now I can just, you see the can execute and you can see here the total from. So now you can
see here this one is first on the ID and remove status from the ID and the manager. So first,
the not defined for inside
in the data. Okay. So now the main factor. So now I can go for the main example. Okay.
So here, I can open for the employee stable all the records. So now here, I can drop a single
column. So now just open for here, just decent and open for another new query. And now here,
first of all, I can start. This is the outer and now here, tag for the outer
table. So here, the table is employees. Okay. So define what the employees are now just here,
drop for the column. Okay. So the drop column for this is the email. Okay. So now here,
define perfectly this email column. And here, I can completely use for the algorithm statement
along with the drop column to remove the email column from the employee stable. Okay.
So now first of all, I can select the statement. And now I'll execute and you can see here,
this column is completely successful. Okay. So now in this operation is successful on the post
query return the confirmation search. Okay. So now just your very face on our select the employees
and then choose and you can see perfectly drop for the email column. Okay. So and next step here,
I can drop for the multiple columns. So now just go for here again, choose for the drop
column. First of all, use for the department, are you okay? So the department underscore ID.
So now just check again. So this department and now the department ID, and now we can use for
another drop column. Okay. So another drop column for the manager side. Okay. So completely used for
the manager underscore ID and they are completely used and these I can use for another table
statement from the drop for both department and then manager ID column from here, the employee
statement. So now just check the statement and you can see here the manager ID in correct some
effects. So now I can go again. So you can see here the step for the manager ID and because
now here we can open for first name. Okay. The first name column and now here, I can use for the
drop column. So now I can here use the column and then just again use this the manager.
So the manager underscore ID. We have just again check. Okay. So just here select and then
secure and you can see here both for this area. Okay. So here simply for
online is the remote. Okay. So drop for this column. So first of all, I can select and secure
and you can see here this command is completely successful. Okay. And here also is for remote
the company ID. So change for this is the sorry, this is the manager. Okay. So the manager
and the starter is so now I can select and execute. And you can see here now the company is
completely successful and post grade will return a confirmation message. Okay. So now let me check
this. So first of all, I can select execute and you can see here a complete open the email
dating department ID and also the manager ID. Okay. So here in this session is completely done.
And now here, I have perfect used for the drop statement in the post grade is serial. Okay.
So there you have it. The perfect of dropping column from the post grade.
A scroll table with some practical example. Okay. So I hope you perfectly understand the session.
So thank you for watching and happy coding. Okay.